mapleleafmommy.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy | Maple Leaf Mommy

The short version?

I promise that I will never sell your info, or do anything dodgy with it. I’m just here to share reviews, rant about my kids, share our travel adventures, and chat with other Canadian parents.

I want to make sure that you have a great experience on this site, now and in the future. I want you to enjoy your experience here, come back and maybe even send your friends over.  I love interacting and sharing with you. I’m not planning on doing anything spammy or slimy with your data, promise.

If you want more details on how I collect and use data on this site, read on:

## Disclaimers, Privacy Policy, Cookie Policy, and GDPR Compliance.

### Disclaimer

By reading and using MapleLeafMommy.com, you are agreeing to the terms listed below:  
​  
I, Deanna Tousignant of MapleLeafMommy.co, am the owner of all intellectual property published on this site, including written work, photography, and video. My work is protected by copyright law and may not be copied, published, reproduced, manipulated, or modified for any purpose, including commercial, without explicit written consent.

The material provided on MapleLeafMommy.com is for the purposes of inspiration and entertainment. It is not a substitute for qualified medical, legal, or professional advice. I accept no responsibility or liability for any damages or losses resulting from relying on the content on MapleLeafMommy.com. All activities carried out based on information contained on this site are done so at your own risk. (If, for example, you choose to cook one of the recipes I’ve shared on here I am totally not responsible if things go terribly wrong and you somehow burn down the house.)

**When I am paid to use a product, to test a product, or to participate in a travel experience, it will be disclosed to my readers.** When I accept payment for a sponsored post or a sponsored link for the purposes of promotion or advertising, it will be disclosed to my readers. If an experience that I write about is a “special bloggers only event” or has been provided at a reduced cost, it will be disclosed to my readers. All disclosures will be explicit on the pages or posts where the product or service has been mentioned.

**I sometimes use affiliate links.** These affiliate links earn me a small commission on purchases that anyone makes after clicking on an affiliate link. Using an affiliate link does not cost the buyer anything. (I get a small commission, you pay the same price you would’ve paid if you hadn’t used my link: win/win.)

**I sometimes host giveaways.** When I hold a giveaway the winner usually needs to provide me with their name, mailing address and phone number, which I then need to share with the company that is providing the prize (unless I am the one providing and shipping the prize, in which case the info stays only with me). This information is used solely for prize fullfilment (aka to ship the prize).

Not that I’m planning on doing this anything soon, but I reserve the right to change the focus of MapleLeafMommy.com, to shut it down, to sell it, or to change the terms of use, at my own discretion.

### Privacy Policy

I respect your privacy.

I am committed to protecting your privacy and your personal data.

I am committed to making sure your data is held securely and for no longer than is necessary.

I am committed to collecting the minimal amount of data that is necessary for the efficient operation of MapleLeafMommy.com.

Data includes, but is not limited to, information provided in comment forms, contact forms, and contest forms, IP address information as collected by my analytics providers and information provided in sign-up forms such as newsletter subscription.

I use Google Analytics to help understand what people look at on my website. IP addresses, in and of themselves, do not allow me in any way to identify you as an individual, but I still treat this information as personal data which I respect and safeguard.

Trust me, I do NOT want anyone hacking my site. That is quite literally one of my worst nightmares. I take every reasonable precaution to protect the security of MapleLeafMommy.com and, by extension, your personal data. This includes using regular Malware Scanning, strong passwords and log-in systems, and an SSL certificate.

All contracts with service providers (such as, for example, my hosting site) include a Data Protection Agreement.

I do not and will not sell my readers’ personal information or contact information to any other company.

I absolutely will not place my readers’ information on spam lists.

You have the right to request that your personal data be deleted and to end subscriptions (such as with newsletters). In the unlikely event of a bleeping catastrophy, I will notify my readers of any security breaches of their personal data within 72 hours of such a breach.

I am attempting to comply to the fullest extent possible with applicable data protection regulations, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (‘GDPR’). That includes using GDPR compliant partners for analytics, newsletter services, and affiliate sales.

## Cookies Policy

### What Are Cookies

As is common practice with pretty much all websites, MapleLeafmommy.com uses cookies. You probably already know this, but just to spell it out — I am not talking about the delicious chocolate chip kind. Cookies, in this case, are tiny files that are placed in the memory of your browser or device. These cookies allow a website or recognize a particular browser or device. Below I describe in detail what information is gathered via cookies, how I use it and why I sometimes need to store these cookies. I also share how you can prevent cookies from being stored (be warned, however, that this may ‘break’ certain elements of site functionality).

#### Disabling Cookies

Unfortunately, in most cases, there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to a website. You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (it varies based on the browser you are using, so see your browser’s Help section for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of a site, and will affect the functionality of MapleLeafMommy.com and many other websites that you visit.

#### The Cookies I Set

**Email newsletters related cookies:**  MapleLeafMommy.com offers a newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.

**Form related cookies:** When you submit data through a form, such as those found on contact pages, comment forms, or giveaway entry forms, cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.

**Site preference cookies:** To provide you with a great experience on MapleLeafMommy.com, I may provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences, I may set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page which would be affected by them. (I am not currently doing this, but may set up the site to have this functionality in the future and am lazy and don’t want to have to come back and rewrite this privacy policy.)

### Third Party Cookies

In some cases, I also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

MapleLeafMommy.com uses Google Analytics to help understand how visitors use the site and ways that I can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and which pages that you visit, so I can continue to (attempt!) to produce the content that you, and my other readers, enjoy.

For more information on how Google Analytics cookies work, see [the official Google privacy policy page](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

I also use StatCounter to track and measure usage of MapleLeafMommy.com (so I can see, for example, how many people are visiting the site and which posts are the most popular). These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site or which pages you visit which helps me to understand how I can improve the site for you.

As well, I use social media buttons and plugins on this site that allow you to connect with social networks in various ways. For these to work, the following social media sites, which may include, but not be limited to, [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php), [Google+](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy), [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875), or [Pinterest](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy), may set cookies through MapleLeafMommy.com which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes. If you want more details on how this works, please refer to the respective privacy policies of these companies (linked above).

### Comments Policy

My blog posts are set up to allow comments. I welcome discussion, debate, and varying opinions. I am not responsible for what others post in the comment section. I do moderate the comments. I reserve the right to delete any comment at any time, without notice or warning. I will delete anything that looks spammy. I also won’t tolerate anything that is racist, derogatory or just plain mean.

When you leave a comment you need to check off the box that says, “I understand that my comment, name & email is stored as data by MapleLeafMommy.com”. This gives permission for your comment, name and email address to be stored. You can use a handle or pen name, I won’t tell anyone. Your email address is not published with the comment (as the admin I can see the email addresses, users of the site can not). I have occasionally used an email to contact someone directly to answer a question. I do not do anything else with that info, it is just there in the comment section. I do not sell the emails. I do not collect them into a list and email people en masse.

Your comment and your personal details (name and email) will remain in the database unless I manually remove it or unless the blog post is removed from the site.

The comment system also uses a cookie. This tracks that you have left a comment previously, so you don’t need to enter your name and email address every time.

Identity theft is a thing — I strongly recommend against leaving personally identifying information, such as your address, birthday, etc., in a comment, on this, or any, site.

At any time you can request that I delete your comment and remove your associated info.

If you have questions about this privacy policy, or about anything concerning my site, please contact me via email at hi@mapleleafmommy.com.

Last updated on May 25, 2018.
